Contact

+91-7574944533 (Mobile) imniravhathi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/imniravhathi (LinkedIn) niravhathi.github.io/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Mobile Applications
Swift
Objective-C

Languages

Hindi

Gujarati

English

Certifications

Easily Identify Spam & Phishing E-Mails

IOS - MOBILE - SWIFT Sep 2020 - White Belt Assessment

NCC "A" Certification

Nirav Hathi

TCS | Ex-Wipro | iOS | Swift | SwiftUI | Mobile App Development | IoT Apps | Wi-Fi | BLE | Objective C

Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

Summary

I have been working professionally as an iOS Developer for over 7 years now. Through those years I have become advanced in developing full feature apps in Objective-C, Swift, SwiftUi. Although I can easily develop all aspects of an iOS app from the networking layer to the front end.

Experience

Tata Consultancy Services
Assistant Consultant
March 2022 - Present (8 months)
Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

- Contribute to the architecture, design and implementation of consumer-facing features in the UPS App
- · Build compelling in-app experiences that will reach users globally
- Collaborate with the product and design team(s) influence the roadmap and product development of UPS's App and services
- · Create and maintain internal shared frameworks and libraries
- Shape the future of optimised analytics at UPS from the ground up with innovative data tools for analytics
- Evolve UPS's architecture to support multiple authentication flows, account management, and integrations
- Mentor, collaborate, and learn from innovative and passionate team members

Wipro Limited
Module Lead
September 2020 - March 2022 (1 year 7 months)
Pune, Maharashtra, India

 Working as Specialist Consultant for HSBC on MobileX app in Customer Support journey.

VOLANSYS Technologies

Senior Software Engineer

April 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Ahmedabad Area, India

- Design and build advanced applications for the iOS platform
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Mobiuso

Software Developer

September 2018 - April 2019 (8 months)

Ahmedabad Area, India

DRC Systems

Senior Software Engineer

October 2015 - August 2018 (2 years 11 months)

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

- Worked closely with our product and design teams to customize apps for iOS platform
- Implemented custom native user interfaces using the latest iOS programming techniques
- Built reusable iOS software components for interface
- Analyzed and optimized UI and back-end application code for efficiency and performance
- Lead development team in architecture and coding patterns and best practices
- Updated project to latest version of swift/Objective C language
- Key decision maker in application architecture guidance and project planning and execution
- Shared knowledge with mobile development team with regard to the company's vision, opportunities and challenges
- Collaborated with other development leads(Android/ Platform/API) on architectural vision and roadmap
- Agile development methodology based on multiple sprints and continuous delivery

Hyperlink Infosystem

Iphone Developer

December 2014 - September 2015 (10 months)

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

- Working with iOS SDK and Objective C
- Started working with Swift, the latest apple programming language released last month
- Experience working with remote data via REST and JSON
- Experience with third-party libraries and APIs
- Working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends and emerging technologies
- Solid understanding of the full mobile development cycle

Education

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedbabd Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.) (2012 - 2015)

Saurashtra University, Rajkot Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2009 - 2012)